maybe you did not know this but if you
are a JavaScript developer that uses npm
or if you are a python developer that
uses pip the chances of you getting
hacked are quite high when I say hacked
I mean getting your personal emails and
accounts hacked your private files being
read copied or deleted private keys and
environment variables being leaked or
even getting a full-blown red remote
access Trojan that can control your
mouse keyboard and take screenshot
developers from other languages are at
risk as well but because of how massive
the python in JavaScript ecosystems are
attackers are targeting developers on
these communities much more aggressively
so today we will learn how this attack
works we will take a look at some of the
malicious code written by the hackers
and at the end we will learn how to
protect ourselves if such thing is even
possible at this point the most valuable
asset a developer has apart from a
mechanical keyboard is time this is why
when a developer has a task they will
first search and see if someone on the
internet has already ready written code
to accomplish a similar task they will
either find some code that does
something similar to what they need or
they will find a package that does
exactly what they need so they can just
install the package save a bunch of time
and keep going being able to install and
use packages that somebody else wrote
instead of writing the code yourself
saves a lot of time but sometimes we as
developers overdo it and end up
depending way too much on third-party
packages the left part issue was proof
of that years ago a developer broke the
JavaScript word when he unpublished a
packaged hero that only had 11 lines of
JavaScript code the package was called
Left pad and all it did is ADD left
padding to a string of text for example
this is what it could do you would give
it a number in maximum length and it
will format the number adding zeros to
the left simple this is the actual code
these 11 lines of code were being
downloaded more than 2 million times per
month it was depended on by many other
projects because this package was
unpublished products like bubble that
are used by all silicon valleys broke as
well the left part issue highlighted
just how much developers reuse each
other's code and how liberal we are on
installing and depending on external
packages to save a bit of time rather to
writing code by hand it also highlighted
how interconnected everything is and how
much packages depend on each other and
of course attackers and malicious actors
took note of that enter supply chain
attacks a supply chain attack is a kind
of attack where a malicious actor
doesn't try to hack your server directly
instead the attacker portions and
compromises these software components
that you use to make your software run
using a supply chain attack and attacker
can compromise your server or the
machine and credentials of the developer
itself according to our research paper
published in 2019 the installation of a
single npm package this typically
requires the installation of 79
third-party packages the desired package
relies on in addition the installation
process involves placing trust in 39
maintainers that you don't know anything
about that creates an incredibly large
surface area for the attack to take
place one way the attack Could Happen
would be by taking control of the
accounts of the people that publish the
code that everybody depends on there is
a package called for each whose code is
this small this package is downloaded
more than 3 million times per week and
is depended on by 36
000 other packages the special thing
about this package is that a security
researcher found out that the account
controlling it was created using an
email from a custom domain name meaning
not an email from Gmail or never but
their own domain name like Nico
jsdev.com for example what the
researcher found out is that the domain
had expired it was back on sale so the
researcher bought the domain and could
effectively take over the account by
sending a reset password email to the
email now owned by him thankfully the
security researcher only did that to
bring attention to the issue but if it
was a malicious actor he could have
easily pushed a silent update to the
library with destructive code that would
have been downloaded millions of times
in the case of an attack where the
account of the developer is compromised
there is very little we developers can
do apart from hoping it doesn't happen
and keeping our dependencies to the
minimum there is another attack Vector
where developers can get their machines
compromised as well as their passwords
and credentials and that is by
installing a package pretending to be
the real one for example math JS is a
very popular math Library some days ago
the package math.js Min was uploaded to
npm on the software World dashmin means
minified a smaller version of of the
package compressed a version that takes
less space so it makes sense that a
developer that wants to make the
application size as small as possible
we'll choose the dash mini version out
of habit attackers know this and this is
why the math js-man package was actually
malware it was a slightly modifier to
look and feel like the math.js package
except that it was also stealing Discord
tokens here you can see how the function
square root number was modified to call
another function that looked for a
Discord token on the browser of the user
and lick them to the attacker getting
the Discord token stolen is not as bad
if you really think about what is going
on and what the attacker could have done
we as developers are downloading code
from strangers and we are running that
code in our computers without actually
taking a look at what the code could do
to our system this is made worse by the
fact that because of how npm works when
you download a package for from the
internet that package can run free and
post installation scripts the package
can run code in your machine before and
after the installation happens on the
background silently Without You noticing
installation scripts can do lots of harm
like in this code which was found on an
installed script of a malicious npm
package here the attackers are taking
your package.json file which contains
information about the product and your
dot EMV file where private keys and
tokens are stored and sending them to
their server you can get bitten by an
attack like this if you don't pay enough
attention as what you are installing and
you spell the name of the package wrong
this is because of a technique attackers
use called typo squatting typo squatting
is when attackers uploads their
malicious code to packages named very
very similar to legit packages hoping
for people to make a keyboard mistake
and download the malicious code for
example selenium and build beautiful
soup are two very famous python packages
and so what attackers did is to publish
packages with these names which as you
can see are misspelled versions of the
original packages but they are spelling
errors that are hard to catch and easy
to make especially in the case of a
beautiful soup what all these packages
contained was this code and what this
code did is to create a browser
extension that runs this code that
browser extension detects all the copy
paste events and when the user has copy
pasted a cryptocurrency address it
intercepts the event and replaces what
the user has copied with the
cryptocurrency address of the attacker
there are many other examples of what
malicious code can do there have been
packages called installing remote access
Trojans keyloggers downloading code from
dodgy URLs and more so how can we
protect ourselves from a supply chain
attack first of all trying to only
install the most necessary third-party
packages and list packages we installed
the less surface area there is for an
attack then do not be a victim of type
of scoring make sure that you spell the
names of the packages you are trying to
install correctly and don't trust
packages that end with the word Dash Min
or any other weird extensions unless you
are sure they are published by the same
developer you can increase your Security
even more by telling node.js and npm to
not run pre and post installation
scripts to do this you can obtain the
dash dash ignore scripts flag next time
you are installing a package like this
when you do this this tells the npm CLI
to skip the execution of three imposed
installation scripts but keep in mind
that this might break the installation
process of packages that make use of the
pre-imposed installation scripts for
legitimate reasons thankfully using
installation scripts is discouraged and
most packages don't use them anymore but
unfortunately that option is always
there for hackers to use it you can also
upgrade to the newly released version 20
of node.js this version comes with a new
experimental feature that allows you to
restrict the permissions your software
has when running using the dash dash
experimental permission flag you can
give or deny the program and its
packages read and write access to your
file system if you use GitHub pay
attention to the Dependable alert
Dependable is an automated system that
runs for all the code hosted on GitHub
this bot will periodically scan your
code and let you know when you are using
a dependency that has a security issue
and it will automatically create a pull
request in your repositories to update
it and finally if you want to go full
paranoid like I did and you don't want
to trust anything you can use Docker
combined with vs code to run all the
projects you are working on inside of a
container that is isolated from your
personal files let me know in the
comments if you would like a video on
how to set that up that's it for this
video now it's your turn to let me know
what do you think about this issue when
you aware of supplying chain attacks do
you think it's possible it can happen to
you let me know in the comments I'm
going to be reading them right now and
don't forget that if you want to learn
things like JavaScript python react
react native go dark flutter among many
others for absolutely free all you have
to do is click the link below to join
any of our many free courses that you
can take right now for absolutely free
with me click the link below and I will
see you there alone
see you on the next one bye
[Music]